+10.5秒 Downloaded from www.opensubtitles.org
Alles bereit.
机身没有问题
Rampe rumen.
引擎没有问题
(tannoy) Achtung! Beistehen zum Feuern.
(注意)
Achtung!
注意
Zndung.
启动
Beistehen.
准备起飞
Motor starten.
引擎开动
Fire three.
三号开炮
(air-raid siren)
（空袭警报）
Hurry up.
快点，快
- Did you bring your driving licence?    - What for?
- 你带了驾驶执照吗？   - 做什么用？
If you fly this thing any lower, you're gonna need it.
如果你再飞低一点，你就会用得上的
Hunt Master to Hounds. Level at angels six.
猎人呼叫猎犬，在六度角水平位
- Roger. - Roger.
- 收到   - 收到
Target at ten o'clock, sir.
长官，目标在十点钟位置
I see it, Tommy.
我看见了，汤米
Look at those bastards. Three V-1s ready to take off.
看那些王八蛋，三架V-1导弹准备起飞
Enough to flatten another square mile of London.
足够把伦敦夷为平地
We're not stopping enough of them, are we, sir?
我们不够力量阻止他们，是吗？
No, we're just thinning them out a little, Wiley.
不，维利，我们只是消弱一下他们的力量
Hunt Master to Hounds. Target identified.
猎人呼叫猎犬，目标确定
(radio) Attack intervals of 15 seconds.
（无线电）每隔15秒后攻击
Bombs away, 1,000 feet.
在高度1000英尺投放炸弹
Here we go!
我们出发吧
Stand by!
准备
Bombs away, sir.
投弹，长官
(gunfire)
（枪炮声）
Stand by with the fly swatter, Wiley.
维利，准备苍蝇拍炸弹
Sir.
是的，长官
Bombs away!
投弹
Hunt Master to Hounds. Let's go home.
猎人呼叫猎犬，我们回家吧
- Roger, Scotty. - Roger, Scotty.
- 斯科特，收到    - 斯科特，收到
Bandits! Bandits! Seven o'clock.
敌机！敌机！注意7点钟位置
Hunt Master to Hounds. Break. Break. Break.
猎人呼叫猎犬，分散，分散
Bannister! Clarke! Get that bastard off Scotty. My fire control's jammed.
班尼斯特！克拉克！掩护斯科特避开敌人。我的发射器失灵了
He's copped it, Quint.
昆特，他被打中了
(Bannister) Quint, let's get out of here.
（班尼斯特）昆特，我们快离开这里
Quint, they're climbing for another pass at us.
昆特，他们在攀升，准备再拦截我们
(Clarke) Dog One, you're leader now, Quint.
（克拉克）猎犬1号，你现在是队长了，昆特
Dog One? Do you read me, Dog One?
猎犬1号？收到了吗？猎犬1号？
Sir, they're calling you!
长官，他们在呼叫你！
Are you all right, sir?
长官，你没事吧？
Dog One to Hounds. Follow me. We're going out low and fast.
猎犬1号呼叫猎犬们，跟着我，我们快速低飞
Stand easy. The strike report you radioed ahead was relayed to Command.
稍息。你之前发来的空袭报告已传送到司令部
You'll be pleased with the signal I received from the air marshal.
听到我转述空军执行官的回复后，你们会很高兴的
''Please convey my personal regards
请把我的致意与问候
to flying officers and men of 641 Squadron. Well done.''
传达向飞行长官和641空军中队成员，表现出色
We didn't even make a dent.
我们的袭击对敌人没产生什么影响
Their launching sites are hard to detect until they go into operation,
除非他们开始操作，否则他们的发射站很难被发现
but I assure you that Command is giving the V-1 problem the highest priority.
但我可以肯定，司令部高度重视敌人的V1武器
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
Well, that's all.
那么，我的话说完了
I'm sorry about Squadron Leader Scott. What happened?
我为队长斯科特的事感到遗憾。发生什么事了？
A flight of Messerschmitts jumped us.
一架梅塞施密特战斗机追上我们了
He was hit before he could manoeuvre. Went down in flames.
他还没反应过来就被击中了，冒烟坠落
- No parachutes?    - No, sir.
- 没跳伞？    - 没有，长官
What does one say? You were close, weren't you?
我该怎么说呢，你们很亲密，是吗？
- We were brought up together. - Really? Were there family connections?
- 我们一起长大的   - 真的？你们有血缘关系吗？
No. My mother and father were killed some time ago.
没有。我的双亲很久以前就被杀了
I've always thought of Squadron Leader Scott's parents as my own.
我把斯科特的父母当成自己的父母
I see.
我明白
Well, I suppose I'd better go and tell them.
我想最好去把这件事告诉他们
It's a hateful business. I can never find the words.
这是讨厌的事，我从来不知怎么开口
What about his wife?
他的妻子怎样？
Would you? I... I... I...
你会，我是说...
All right.
好的
Hello, Quint.
你好，昆特
Hi, Quint.
Hello, Quint.
你好，昆特
What did you say to my sister?
你对我妹妹说了什么？
I didn't have to say anything.
我不必说什么
Scotty?
斯科特？
You still at the hospital?
你还要住院吗？
Yes, convalescent. I brought this crowd over. I wish to God I hadn't.
是的，康复期。我准备了聚会庆祝，真希望我没有这样做
- When do you return to duty?    - Duty? What duty?
- 你什么时候恢复职务？    - 职务？什么职务？
- Flying a desk one-handed.    - If that's all you think you can handle.
- 用一只手开飞机吗？   - 只要你想那样做，你就可以做到
They've offered me a hook.
他们给了我一个铁钩
Makes a marvellous backscratcher, so I'm told.
他们告诉我背痒了就可以用来抓痒
I'm sure Scotty would settle for it right now.
我肯定斯科特还在的话，会马上准备好的
He's dead.
他遇难了
Did you see it?
你看见了吗？
Yes.
是的
No parachute?
没有跳伞吗？
There wasn't time.
来不及了
Did...
做...
Did it burn?
着火了吗？
It blew up when it hit the ground.
飞机着地时爆炸了
- Beth...    - Leave me alone.
- 贝丝...    - 让我一个人静静
Please.
求你了
How did she take it?
她怎么了？
- Do you think I should go to her?    - No, I don't. Just let her cry.
- 你认为我该去陪她吗？   - 不，你不应该去陪她，让她痛哭一场吧
You're a hard-nosed bastard, Quint.
昆特，你是个无情的混蛋
Scotty was practically your brother.
斯科特就像你的亲兄弟一样
That's right, Douglas.
没错，道格拉斯
Scotty was practically my brother.
斯科特就像我的亲兄弟
Ah, Munroe. Meet Major Kemble, Military Intelligence.
文路，见见肯布尔少将，军事情报员
The major's got a little job. I thought you were the man for it.
少将有项任务，我想你是他的合适人选
- How do you do?     - Sir.
- 你好     - 长官
Nothing very exciting, I'm afraid.
我恐怕这工作并不是那么令人兴奋
Milk run, really.
实际上是例行的侦察
I want to go over, take a look at this place.
我想飞到这里上空侦察一下
- Chateau de Charlon. - (Quint) Very pretty.
- 沙尔龙堡    - 真漂亮
Yes. What we're interested in is the, er...
是的，我们感兴趣的是...
underskirts.
内侧
- You've been briefed on the V-2 rockets?    - Yes, sir.
- 你了解了V-2火箭？   - 是的，长官
Intelligence has it that there's a V-3, even a V-4, in development.
有情报说，V3型，甚至V4正在开发中
Larger, more punch. More important: longer range.
更大，更具杀伤力，更重要的是，射程更远
We think the development work is done at Chateau de Charlon.
我们认为这发展项目应该在沙尔龙堡内进行
That's why I want to take a look.
这就是我想查看的原因
The Major will be flying with you.
少将会和你一起飞行
I understood. I had a few hours off base, sir.
我明白，但我想离开基地几个小时
The weather's closed in over France. We have to fit the cameras to your aircraft.
法国上空天气不好，我们要花几个小时在你的飞机上安装照相机
- 24 hours enough for you? - Yes, sir.
- 给你24小时够吗？   - 够的，长官
I'm going to see my... Squadron Leader Scott's parents.
我要去看望我的...飞行队队长，斯科特的父母
- What time is it?    - Half past four.
- 几点了？   - 四点半
They'll just be having tea on the terrace.
这个时候，他们正在阳台喝茶
Come on.
来吧
- (woman sobs) - Walk with me, Quint, will you?
-（女人抽泣）  - 陪我走走，昆特，行吗？
(Quint) We were pulling out    - you know, ready to go home -
（昆特）我们那时将要离开   - 你知道，准备回来...
when a flight of Messerschmitts jumped us.
可是一架梅塞施米特式战机追上了我们
They came out of the sun. It was so quick Scotty had no time to manoeuvre.
我想他们是从太阳那边追来的。太快了，让斯科特反应不过来
He just appeared to go straight down into the ground.
他直冲向地面，那里...
He had no time, no time at all, to pull out.
我完全来不及逃跑
I'm sure that, er, it was instantaneous.
我肯定，这是一瞬间内发生的事
When your parents died and you came to live with us,
当你的父母去世后，你来和我们一起住...
Mother and I always admired your spirit, the way you handled your grief...
妈妈和我都钦佩你的精神和面对悲痛的勇气
and went on with your life.
然后继续正常工作
That's what they would have wanted me to do.
他们就是希望我这样做
I, erm...
我...
I only hope we can do as well, Quint.
只是希望我们能做得一样好，昆特
- You'll be leading the squadron now.   - Yes.
- 你现在是飞行队队长了？   -是的
Good. Mother and I will be proud of you.
很好，妈妈和我都会以你为荣
There's Charlon.
那就是沙尔龙堡
How close do you wanna go?
你想飞多近？
Part their hair, Squadron Leader.
能把他们的头发分开为止，长官
(plane approaches)
(飞机靠近)
Noisy lot, weren't they?
他们很吵，是吧？
That's a lot of flak for one chateau.
对一座城堡来说，这里太多高射炮了
They must have something they don't want seen.
他们一定有些不想被发现的东西
Which is a good reason for us to have to go in again.
这正是我们再来这里的原因
How close do you wanna go this time?
这次你要飞多近？
Knock their bloody heads off.
近到打掉他们的头
Have you had enough yet?
拍够照片了吗？
- You OK, Major?    - Let's go home.
- 少将，你还好吧？  - 我们回家吧
(engine splutters)
(引擎的嘈杂声)
More trouble, I'm afraid. I think they've got the hydraulics.
恐怕故障很大。我认为液压系统被打坏了。
It's gonna be a bumpy landing.
我们要做一个颠簸降落
Major. Major!
少将，少将！
- Kemble?    - He's in there.
- 肯布尔？    - 他在那儿
Smash the cockpit. Smash the cockpit!
打碎驾驶舱，打碎驾驶舱！
Let's hope those bloody pictures are worth it.
希望这血腥的照片没有白费
Away you go!
你开吧！
That's the squadron leader's ready room through there, ma'am.
女士，那是队长的休息室
I'll... I'll wait outside.
我会在外面等你
Thank you.
谢谢你
(chair scrapes)
(椅子发出声音)
Oh, it's you.
噢，是你
I... I came for Scotty's things.
我...我是来拿斯科特的东西
I was gonna bring them over.
我会把它们拿回去
I'm sorry but... I just wanted to see this place.
对不起，但... 我只想看看这里
- I forgot that you would...  - No, no, that's... that's all right.
- 我忘了你会...   - 不，不...没关系
I, erm... I saw Scotty's batman on the way over.
我... 我在路上碰见斯科特的勤务员
He was going to fetch a uniform of Scotty's.
我正要去拿回斯科特的制服
It was at the cleaner's.
还在洗衣店
- How's Douglas?    - He's gone back to the hospital,
- 道格拉斯怎么样？   - 他已经回医院了，
to get one of those artificial hands fitted.
去测量造假手了
He said you convinced him.
他说你说服了他
- I did?    - You jolted him, Quint.
- 我有吗？   - 你让他动摇了，昆特
- Oh!    - That's what he needed.
- 噢！   - 他就需要这样的
You look tired.
你好像很累
Have you been flying?
你一直都在飞行吗？
Yes, just routine. It was a milk run, really.
是的，只是例行飞行。没危险性的飞行勤务
I should have known better. You're resting. I'll come back...
我应该知道的，你在休息，我要回去了
No, no, that's all right. There's, er, there's some more stuff in there.
不，不，没关系，那里还有更多东西
Scotty called this room his confessional -
斯科特请求这房间做他的忏悔室
the place where he faced up to himself.
一个他真正面对自己的地方
- He envied you, Quint.   - He envied me?
- 他羡慕你，昆特   - 羡慕我？
Well, he had all the brains.
他聪明绝顶
I cribbed off him all the way through school.
我在学校的时候总是模仿他
He told me all about that. And about the girls you passed on to him.
他都告诉我了，还有你传给他的女孩们
I didn't pass, exactly. He took them.
我事实上没有传给他，是他把她们抢走了
Me too?
我也是其中一个？
I put the rest of his things in here.
我把他的其他东西放在这儿
Oh, sorry.
对不起
No, no. That's mine.
不，不，这是我的
Burned?
少了？
Oh, no, Quint. Not you too.
不要，昆特，也不是你
(knock at door)
(敲门声)
- Yes?    - Vesey, sir.
- 谁？   - 威思，长官
Oh, er...
哦，呃…
Yes, Vesey. Come in.
好的，威思，请进
The squadron leader's uniform, sir. Mrs Scott asked me to...
空军部队队长的制服，先生。斯科特女士叫我...
I'll get dressed and... and drive you home.
我穿好衣服... 然后开车送你回家
How many miles does it do to the gallon?
走一英里要用多少加仑汽油？
Not many.
不多
- Why don't you sell it? - Shh. She'll hear you.
- 为何不把车卖了？   - 车会听到的
She's a temperamental old bitch as it is.
她是一只喜怒无常的婊子
I'm sorry. Mess life coarsens the vocabulary somewhat.
对不起。那只是让词汇稍微变得粗糙的混乱生活
I know. It played havoc with Scotty's.
我知道。这让斯科特陷入了大混乱
You know what I regret most?
你知道我最遗憾的是什么吗？
Not knowing what sort of father he'd have made.
不知道他是怎样的一个父亲
I'd love to have seen him with his children.
我很想看见他和他的孩子们在一起
We'd even picked the names.
我们甚至给孩子挑选了名
If there's anything you need or want, you will call me, won't you?
如果你有需要的话，打电话给我，好吗？
Yes. But don't worry, I'll be all right.
是的，不过别担心，我不会有事的
And you don't have to be so formal.
而且，你不必这么拘谨
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's just that I...
只是...
Well, I feel sort of embarrassed.
我觉得有点局促不安
It's the first time we've ever really been alone together.
这是我们第一次真正单独在一起
When Scotty was with us, we were all part of the same family. Now it...
斯科特在生时，我们都是家庭的一份子，可是现在
It doesn't feel right somehow.
不知何故地觉得不对劲
You feel guilty.
你觉得心虚了
Oh, Quint! That's very revealing.
昆特，这很有启示
Yes, it is, isn't it? I'm sorry.
对，难道不是吗？对不起
Don't keep apologising. I understand.
不要老道歉，我理解
- You do?    - Yes.
- 是吗？   - 是的
The day Scotty joined the squadron his old navigator married a girl,
斯科特加入空军那天，他的导航员和一个女孩结婚了...
just two weeks after her first husband was killed.
就是在那女孩前夫被杀的两个星期前
He was a pilot.
他是个飞行员
I remember being absolutely shocked.
我记得我对此非常震惊
Four days after the wedding, he got shot down.
结婚4天后，导航员被击毙了
Then I understood.
然后我明白
Time is so precious.
时间是多么的宝贵
It's about the only thing they don't give us ration coupons for.
这都是关于一件事，他们不给我们定量的优惠
Air Commodore Hufford, this is Squadron Leader Munroe...
这是准将哈佛德，这是飞行队队长文路
You flew Kemble over Charlon, didn't you, Munroe?
你和肯布尔一起去了沙尔龙堡，是吗，文路？
- Yes, sir. That's correct. - Good man, was Kemble.
- 是的，长官，是这样   - 肯布尔很优秀
He'd have been decorated for the results he got - excellent.
他立下了大功，太棒了！
Come and have a look at this.
来看看这个
We made this model from Kemble's photographs.
我们根据肯布尔拍摄的相片造了这个模型
Hold those a minute, Mason.
拿著那些东西一会儿，梅森？
Now, what do you suppose that is?
你觉得那是什么？
- It looks like a tunnel, sir.   - Course it's a tunnel.
- 看上去像是隧道，长官    - 当然是隧道了
We know more about it than that.
我们知道得更多
Down there, that's where they're hatching their new bird.
在这下面，就是他们孵化新小鸟的地方
What we want you to do, Munroe, is to chuck a bomb in there
文路，我们想要你做的，就是在那儿放置个炸弹
and addle their eggs for 'em.
并且完全地破坏他们的鸟蛋
In there?
在那里面？
Command plans a low-level saturation-bombing mission
司令部计划了低高度的渗透炸弹任务
by at least two squadrons of Mosquitoes.
至少要两个飞蚊飞行队去完成
Now, you'd lead a specially trained flight for this specialist task.
现在你得为这特别任务，领导一个受特别训练的飞行队去完成
It's near impossible to put a bomb in there.
放置炸弹在那里面，这似乎不可能
Nonsense. Blinds down, Mason.
胡说！梅森，把窗帘放下
We'll run that film again.
我们会再放一次那胶片
This is top-secret film, Munroe.
文路，这是高度机密影片
What you're going to see is a development of Barnes Wallis.
你会看到的是在巴纳沃利丝的发展计划
The hydraulics start the bomb spinning.
水力使炸弹旋转投下
But here's the joker:
但这就是开巧妙之处
this bomb bounces on land.
这种炸弹在地面弹起
- In a straight line?   - Yes. Regardless of terrain.
- 直线地弹走吗？   - 是的，不受任何地形影响
It's beautiful. It's so beautiful, I've run this print a thousand times.
漂亮，太漂亮了，我们已经试了上千次
The civilian scientists have ironed most of the wrinkles out for you.
科学家们已帮你解决不少问题
Your job will be to perfect the technique under combat conditions.
这工作会使科技在战争状态下得到完善
Well, I think we've seen enough. Thank you, Mason.
我想我们已看得够多了，梅森，谢谢你
There you are. Barnes Wallis, God bless him,
你将要去那里。巴纳沃利丝，上帝保佑他，
has done your job for you, practically.
完成你的任务
Your bombs would have a time fuse.
你的炸弹会有个定时导火索
If you went in at exactly 60 feet...
如果你进入60英尺范围内...
60 feet...?
60英尺？
It'd take months to get that accurate.
要如此精确，必须练习几个月才行
You have ten days to practise. And I'll tell you why just ten days.
你有十天时间练习。让我告诉你为什么只有十天
The French underground reports the first of the Germans' new weapons
法国地下报道德国第一个新武器
will be ready in 12 days.
将在12天内研制完成
You'll have special bombsights and dummy bombs.
你将有特殊的炸弹瞄准器和虚拟炸弹练习
Building a replica of the Charlon tunnel now.
他们现在建有虚拟沙尔龙堡隧道
Any justice in the world, you'll be a national hero.
为了世界的正义，你是国家的英雄
What do you say, Munroe? Hm? What are the odds?
文路，你认为怎样？成功率有多大？
The same as spitting in an air commodore's eye from an express train.
就像在高速火车上射击准将的眼睛一样难
I like that. Yes, I do like that. Sense of humour.
我喜欢，我真的喜欢，有幽默感
He'll do nicely, Wing Commander. Just the man.
你会很好地完成任务，飞行指挥官，他是合适人选
Now, get your team together and practise.
现在，去召集你的队员进行训练吧
Stop that rocket flying and you'll take years off the war.
击落那火箭式飞机，你会有好几年不用上战场的
Remember that. Years.
记住，是好几年
You've got ten days to chuck your bomb down that tunnel.
你有十天时间去把炸弹放进隧道
All right.
好的
Air scoop out.
打开投弹仓
Air scoop out, sir.
投弹仓已打开，长官
- RPM?    - 800.
- 飞行速度？   - 800
Stand by.
预备
Steady.
保持稳定
Bomb away.
投弹
Missed.
没打中
(Quint) Bannister, change your angle of approach. 60 feet.
班尼斯特，改变你的角度，要更接近60英尺
- Drop from 60 feet, Bannister. - Roger.
- 班尼斯特，从60英尺处投下   - 收到
Stand by. Steady...
预备，稳定...
Bomb away!
投弹
That's wide. Too wide. Correct your angle of attack.
离得太远了，修正你的攻击角度
I thought I was right on the money, skipper.
船长，我想我的钱没白费
Steady.
保持稳定
Bomb away!
投弹
- What was your range that    - 1100, right on 60 feet.
- 班尼斯特，你那次的射程是多远？   - 1100，刚好60英尺
I'm gonna try the same numbers.
我也会试试同样的数字
Bomb away.
投弹
Missed.
没打中
Ah, Squadron Leader. My congratulations, sir.
啊，空军队长，恭喜你，先生
Your usual table, sir. This way, if you please.
你以前的餐桌，先生。请走这边
We haven't seen you all in so long, I thought you'd found another place.
很久没见你来了，我以为你改了别的餐厅。
- With better market contacts than ours.    - That's not possible and you know it.
- 就是那些生意更好的店    - 你知道那是不可能的
We try to do our best, sir. Especially for our service clientele.
先生，我们竭尽所能。尤其为了我们的客人们
Is Squadron Leader Scott joining you?
空军队长斯科特会来一起就餐吗？
No.
不
- What's not on the menu tonight, Victor?    - Chicken.
- 维特，今晚有什么特别菜单吗？   - 鸡肉
- Roasted?    - To perfection.
- 烤的？   - 完美极了
- Then chicken it is.   - Thank you. Thank you.
- 那就烤鸡吧   - 谢谢，谢谢
Scotty never did like chicken anyway.
斯科特从不喜欢吃鸡
I think the waiter thinks we're having an affair.
我想那服务员以为我们有恋情
Are you ever afraid?
你害怕过吗，昆特？
Scotty used to be sick with fear before every flight.
斯科特每次执行飞行任务前都会很不舒服
- Did you know that?    - Yes.
- 你知道吗？   - 知道
Funny thing, though. When you're flying, you're free.
很有趣，当你飞行时，你很自由
You're trained to handle every emergency.
你被训练到能处理任何紧急情况了
You're prepared for each eventuality.
你要对各种可能发生的事有准备
It's a pattern that you can react to.
这是一个你能做出反应的模式
Down here the confusion starts.
在地面，心情反而会变得混乱
Aha! Avast there, ye landlubbers! Ye'll walk the plank for this.
且慢，旱鸭子，你要用这支架走路
- What do you think? Bit clumsy at first.    - You'll adjust.
- 你认为怎样？一开始会控制困难    - 你会适应的
I have. I'm reporting for duty tomorrow.
我已适应了，我要转移，我明天要报告工作
- Where?    - Quint's group. In charge of Link training.
- 在哪里？   - 昆特的队伍中，主管反应训练
- That's good news. When did you apply?    - Dear boy, they asked for me.
- 那真是好消息，你什么时候申请的？   - 申请？亲爱的先生，是他们请求我
- ''Lend a hand'' I think the phrase was.    - Doug!
- 我想这可说是助一臂之力吧    - 道格
- Oh, I forgot. Susan.    - Hello.
- 噢，我忘了介绍，这是苏珊   - 你好
She's a nurse. She likes the ironmongery. She's got an itchy back.
她是护士，她更喜欢铁制品。她的背部常发痒
- Doug, stop it!    - Would you, er, care to join us?
- 不要说了，道格！   - 你们介意和我们一起吃饭吗？
No, I'm not having Beth tell the secrets of the nursery.
不好了，贝丝还没告诉我护士的秘密
Besides, we'll ruin your evening. Well, cheerio.
还没有，我们会破坏了你们的晚饭
- Shark meat, the pair of you.    - Oh, Doug!
- 你俩是一对鲨鱼肉   - 别乱说了
When Doug bounces back he really bounces.
道格振作起来的时候，他真的会很活跃的
You suggested him for that job.
你建议他接受那训练工作
- Well, I sort of...    - I'm very grateful, Quint... for so much.
-我只是稍微...   - 我很感激你，昆特...为了这一切
Food!
食物来了！
Mm! Looks delicious!
看起来很美味的！
- That's enough rough air. Bring him in.    - Locks in, please.
- 好的，飞行训练够了，带他进里面    - 请锁定
Do you feel godlike controlling the weather?
你觉得上帝在支配天气吗？
- Quint!    - How's the job going?
- 昆特！   - 工作进展怎样？
Apart from being rated next to the dentist on the fliers' pet-hate list, OK.
还好吧，飞行员最讨厌牙医，其次就到我了
- Tests and reaction tests on your men.    - What's this about Templeton?
- 要对你的队员进行反应测试   - 谢谢，布烈顿的情况怎么样？
Reactions slow and ill-timed. Borderline. Your decision.
他反应慢，错失时机，由你决定吧
He seems all right in the air. Maybe it's exam nerves.
他在飞行中表现还好，可能是考试紧张吧
Well, as I said, your decision. But you are doing a precision job.
正如我说的，你做决定。但你们要做的是精密的工作
- You'd do him a favour if he could rest.   - I wonder how much of a favour it'd be.
- 如果让他休息一下的话，对他很有用的   - 我不知道这会有多大作用
- Oh, put him through again. - Right.
- 让他通过把   - 好的
- How's Susan?    - We're getting engaged.
- 苏珊怎样？   - 我们订婚了
- Why the rush?    - No rush. I've got time now.
- 为何这么匆忙？   - 不匆忙，我们现在有时间
- Time?    - My ticket. With luck I'll survive the war.
- 时间？   - 我的入场券。很幸运，我在战争中幸存下来了
Fliers should never marry. You saw what it did to Beth when Scott...
飞行员不该结婚。你看到斯科特对贝丝做了什么…
I'm sorry.
对不起
That's all right. I... I agree with you.
不要紧，我同意你的说法
Yes?
是吗？
Well, what I thought we should... Thank you.
我认为我们应该...谢谢
I thought we should get a bottle of champagne,
我想我们可以开瓶香槟，
and make a foursome - you and Beth, me and Susan.
我们组成四人组，你和贝丝，我和苏珊
Sounds a good idea.
不错的主意
Erm, Quint.
昆特
I'm being delicately reminded there is one member of our flight not yet checked out.
我想起我们中队还有一人还没接受检测
- Who's that?    - You.
- 是谁？   - 你
No, you're way overdue. When shall I write you in for?
我帮你预定个时间，你想什么时候？
As soon as you want to get stood up. See you.
一旦你想站起来的时候，再见
Stand by.
预备
Steady.
保持稳定
Bomb away!
投弹！
Bull's-eye. Good shot.
很准，射的好！
- Their average is one hit in ten, sir.    - We only need one hit.
- 他们平均有十分一次中，长官   - 我们只需中一次击中
Three planes can only carry six highballs, sir.
长官，三架飞机只能运六枚弹
Flight Lieutenant Mason is still pessimistic,
飞行副官梅森还是那么悲观
but I say your chaps will continue to improve.
但我认为你的队员们会继续改进的
Correct, Wing Commander?
空军司令，对吗？
Ohh!
哦!！
Beth!
贝丝！
I'm all right.
我没事
Friends?
朋友？
- Good luck.    - And blessings.
- 祝你好运   - 祝福你们
Come on. Kiss her.
来吧，吻她
- Quint, it's a public place.    - No, come on. She's your fianc now.
- 昆特，这是公共场所   - 不是啦，她现在是你的未婚妻了
That's the idea of this stuff. It's supposed to fizz away your inhibitions.
就是这东西，酒正是用来驱逐你平时的拘束
Get away! That's enough. I'd say you two have been practising.
分开，够了。我得说你俩真够熟练
Stop it, Quint. You're making Susan blush.
别闹了，昆特。你让苏珊脸红了
- Is he always like this?    - Yes, he is.
- 他老是这样吗？   - 对，他总是这样
We're gonna leave you two the bottle. I never did believe in long engagements.
我们把这瓶酒留给你们。我不相信婚约会长久的
- Susan, I've had enough.  - She's hinting at something.
- 苏珊，我喝够了    - 我觉得她在暗示些东西
- I promised to get you home by midnight.    - Midnight?
- 我保证让你在午夜前回到家   - 午夜？
Yes. All flyboys in their kips by 12.
对，所有飞行员都要在12点前睡觉
Have fun, you two.
你俩玩得开心点
(soldiers) I belong to Glasgow
我们属于加拉斯高
Dear old Glasgow town
亲爱的古老加拉斯高镇
But there's something the matter with Glasgow
但加拉斯高出了点问题
Cos it's going round and round
因为它在旋转不息
I'm only a common old working chap
我只是个普通老工人
As anyone here can see
这里所有的人都能看见我
But when I get a couple of drinks on a Saturday
但当我星期六喝了两瓶酒后
Glasgow belongs to me
拉加斯高属于我的了
The only way Charlon can be levelled and the underground laboratory penetrated
夷平沙尔龙堡和渗透地下实验室的唯一方法
is by extremely accurate saturation bombing.
就是用非常精确的渗透炸弹
Squadron Leader Munroe, with Bannister and Clarke,
空军队长文路以及班尼斯特和克拉克，
will take off with highball bombs to destroy the tunnel.
会投下炸弹摧毁隧道
The second wave, consisting of 636, 579 and 663 squadrons,
第二击，就由636，579，663空军部队组成
will follow exactly ten minutes later to hit Charlon at low level - below 500 feet.
在紧接着的十分钟后，进行500英尺低飞，攻击沙尔龙堡
Now, I realise... I realise that dropping from that level can be sticky,
现在，我意识到，飞得这么低会有危险的
but that is our assignment.
但那是我们的任务
Air Commodore Hufford has a word to say to you.
现在，哈佛德准将有话要对你们说
And it's a bad one. Jerry knows you're coming.
这是个坏消息，德军知道你们会来攻击
A key Resistance man was picked up by the Gestapo. We must assume he talked.
一位主要的抗战者被纳粹党秘密警察逮捕。我们假设他招供了
The Germans will increase their defences.
德国人毫无疑问会提高防范
With every passing day, they'll get hotter.
在接下来的日子里，他们会越来越警惕
That makes it imperative you get in there as soon as possible
这使得你们必须尽快进入那里
and make the destruction of Charlon as total as you can.
并且尽可能摧毁沙尔龙堡
Well, that's all. I know you're the men that'll do it.
我的话说完了，我知道你们会胜任的
Good luck to you all.
祝你们好运
'Shun!
散会
Ground's as hard as a billiard table.
地面像桌球台一样硬
You have reservations about our mission?
你对我们的任务有保留吗？
No, sir. I don't think we stand a loving chance.
不，长官。我们很有可能成功
Air raid!
空袭！
(gunfire)
(枪声)
Look out, Quint!
昆特，小心！
It's a roll of film!
这是一卷胶片
My God! Those are RAF prisoners.
天啊！那些是英国皇家空军的战俘
That's Webb - Alan Webb. He was my wing man.
他是韦伯，阿伦韦伯，他曾是我的飞行员
- There's Crawford and Greenwood and...    - They're all RAF aircrews.
- 那是克劳德和格林伍德   - 他们都是英国皇家空军部队成员
That's Scotty!
那是斯科特！
- What the hell are they playing at?    - That's perfectly obvious.
- 他们在干什么？   - 这很明显
Switch that damn thing off. I've seen quite enough.
把那关掉吧。我已经厌了
There you see the crude subtlety of the Nazi mind, gentlemen, well illustrated.
你可以看见纳粹既残暴，又奸诈狡猾
- But what can they hope to gain?    - Two things.
- 但他们希望能得到什么？   - 两样东西
Lowered morale amongst our aircrews
第一，想消弱我们空军的士气
and a propaganda opportunity - the Royal Air Force bombing their own men.
第二就是要宣传皇家空军部队攻击自己人
Headline: The Fratricidal RAF.
大字标题：皇家空军互相残杀
- It's monstrous!    - Penrose, there is one gift in all this.
- 太可怕了！   - 不过，在这里面有一种极大的天赋
This infantile stratagem confirms our own supposition about Charlon.
这种幼稚的计谋更确定了我们对沙尔龙堡的猜想
We know now Charlon is vital to the Nazi machine.
我们现在得知沙尔龙堡有对纳粹党起生死攸关的装备
Charlon must be destroyed!
沙尔龙堡一定要摧毁！
We'd be murdering our own men!
我们在杀害我们自己的人
Not a word of what we've seen must go outside this room.
出了这房间就不可以说我们看到的东西，你明白吗？
Under no circumstances, to anybody.
在任何情况下，任何人都不行
What a hell of a mess.
实在太混乱了
Quint. We've got to tell Beth that Scotty's alive.
昆特，我们得告诉贝丝，斯科特还活着
Do you think that would be a kindness?
你觉得这是好意吗？
Quint, he's alive. You've got to tell her!
昆特，他还活着。你要告诉他！
I know he's alive! What do you want me to tell her?
我知道他活着！你要我跟她说什么？
That he's in Charlon? My next mission is to bomb Charlon.
告诉她他在沙尔龙堡? 我下个任务就是去轰炸沙尔龙堡
Who's gonna tell her that Scotty died twice?
谁会去告诉她斯科特要死两次？
They won't go through with the strike now.
现在他们不会攻击沙尔龙堡的
You're a romantic, Douglas.
道格拉斯，你真浪漫
Command isn't.
但司令部不是那样
What a hell of a... rotten mess.
真是一团糟！
Now you're repeating yourself.
不要这样，你在自言自语反复说着
Poor Beth.
可怜的贝丝
(Beth) Quint!
昆特！
Quint!
Quint?
昆特！
What's the matter?
怎么了？
It's so peaceful here.
这么和平，宁静
But you've brought the war with you.
但你把战争带来了
It's this next flight, isn't it?
担心这次的飞行任务，是吗？
I know the signs.
我看得出迹象
Come on. Come on! Let's run.
来吧！我们跑吧！
''Alter Wein und junge Frauen die Mner frlich machen. ''
（德语）
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
It means ''Old wine and young women make a man happy.''
意思是：老酒和年轻女人让男人开心
Do you think he... got out in time?
你认为驾驶员及时逃脱了吗？
Maybe.
可能吧
Quint!
昆特！
Maybe in France... there's a couple strolling,
可能在法国... 有对夫妇在散步
and they... they see Scotty's plane.
然后... 他们看见斯科特的飞机
(Penrose) Command knows the position the enemy has placed us in.
司令部知道敌人把我们放在什么位置
Hufford was right. The mission itself is costly enough in men and machines.
哈佛德说得对，这项任务要牺牲很多人命和机器
And there's the prisoners, the murder - oh, yes, that is the word -
还有那些战俘，应该这样说，是谋杀
the murder of our men, and the propaganda to be made out of it.
他们想宣传“杀害自己人”
Nevertheless, the orders remain: destroy Charlon.
不过，命令仍然是毁灭沙尔龙堡
- Regardless of the cost?    - Regardless.
- 不计代价？    - 不计代价
Now that is a measure of how important this thing is.
现在要计量一下这任务的重要性
Group has been notified.
我们队已被通知
They hit the target ten minutes after your highball attack on the tunnel.
他们在你们轰炸隧道后的10分钟攻打目标
Takeoff at 0600 hours tomorrow, weather permitting.
天气许可的话，在明早6点整出发
It's off! The whole bloody Continent's socked in. It's off!
停止！整个浴血大陆的攻击停止。整个攻击停止。
- You mean it's postponed?    - For how long?
- 你意见是计划延迟吗？   - 延迟多久？
I don't know. It's thick and soupy for as far ahead as we can forecast. It's off!
我不知道。天有不测风云
Ah!
啊！
For the first time, I'm almost glad of this thing.
首先，我为这东西觉得高兴
- Hey! A Scotch for the squadron leader. - You trying to drink the bar dry?
- 嘿！一个苏格兰人当空军队长   - 你想把酒吧的酒喝光吗？
Funny you should say that, Quint, cos that is exactly what I intend to do.
很有趣，你该这样说，昆特，我正准备这样做呢
Well, for the first time in my life, I'm glad I'm not flying any more.
我平生首次为不再执行飞行任务而高兴
That's right, Quint, look around.
对的，昆特，看看周围
Take a good look at those faces.
好好看看那些脸孔
Think of the other faces that have been in this room, faces you and I saw recently.
想想其他曾在这房间出现的脸孔，那些我和你最近见过的面孔。
- Faces of friends of ours, close friends. - Take it easy, Doug.
- 我们朋友的面孔，亲密的朋友   - 放松，道格
You know what's the matter with them? Pre-op nerves. Weather wait.
你知道他们怎么了？飞行前紧张等待天气好转
- If they knew what we know...    - I'm gonna take you to your room.
- 如果他们知道我们知道的秘密...   - 不介意的话，我带你回我房间
What would happen if they knew about the POWs in Charlon?
如果他们知道我们的战俘在沙尔龙堡，那会发生什么？
- Shut up.    - There'd be a ruddy riot.
- 闭嘴   - 那会是血腥的暴乱
- I'm sure there would. That's enough.    - It's not enough!
- 他们不会的，够了   - 不够
''Shut up!'' ''Be a good boy!'' That's what's wrong with this war, Quint.
闭嘴！安静，听话吧。那是这场战争的问题
Those who can see not telling these blind fools where they're falling. You daren't...
知道真相的人不告诉这群盲目的傻瓜，他们降落在哪里。你不敢告诉他们，是吗？
Get off me!
放开我！
Do you know what the Nazis have moved into Charlon?
听着，你们知道纳粹党把什么转移到沙尔龙堡了吗？
- You don't know what you're saying.   - POWs, that's what!
- 闭嘴，你不知道自己在说什么   - 我方的战俘，那就是我要说的
Airmen - Mosquito pilots. They're making you into murderers!
空军，飞蚊队飞行员们，他们把你们变成杀人凶手
- Is this true, Quint?    - Course it is. Look at his face.
- 昆特，是真的吗？   - 肯定是，看他的脸色
Gentlemen!
先生们！
Escort this officer to his quarters.
我送这军官回他的营房
There'll be a briefing in one hour for all duty officers.
一小时后，所有值班军官会收到指示任务
Well, that is the situation. You know it all now. You would have been told.
处境就是这样。你们应该都知道情况了。你们都知道了
And the directive remains: Charlon must be destroyed.
而命令是：必须摧毁沙尔龙堡
- But, sir, suppose...    - Templeton, do your job and I'll do mine.
- 长官，但是...   - 布列顿，做你的事，我做我的
Now, just look at this matter. If the work at Charlon continues,
现在看看这个问题，如果沙尔龙堡的工程继续下去的话
hundreds of thousands of people might die, all of southern England devastated,
成千上万的人就会死去，整个英国南部会被蹂躏，
our bridgehead in Europe destroyed, the invasion delayed months.
我们的欧洲根据地被破坏，我们的攻击会延迟数月
- Couldn't the paratroops go in?    - They'd be slaughtered.
- 不可以让伞兵加入攻打吗？   - 他们会被屠杀的
- The French underground?    - The Germans are on the alert.
- 那法国的地下游击队呢？   - 德国人正在警戒着
No, it must be a strike from the air.
不，一定是从空中攻击
There may be a way, sir. While we attack, we detach one aircraft to breach the wall,
或者有一个办法，当我们攻击隧道时，我们会分出一架飞机去破坏墙壁，
the French underground cross the breach,
法国的地下游击队穿过那缺口，
take on the Germans in the castle and help our chaps out.
和德国人在城堡内较量并救出战俘
- Just ahead of our bombing attack?    - Yes.
- 就在我们炮轰前？   - 对
- Then what?    - Well, then it's every man for himself.
- 然后呢？   - 然后各自逃跑
Scuttling out? Running in all directions?
逃跑？向四面八方跑？
At least this way they won't die under our own bombs.
这个方法起码他们不用死在我们炮轰之下
Yes. All right. I can see some sense in it.
对，我看得出这里面的道理
Then you get Headquarters to approve the plan.
那您让司令部批准这个计划吧
They'll need the cooperation of the French underground.
他们需要法国的地下游击队的合作
The underground couldn't mount an effort on this scale.
地下游击队不能承受这些任务
Even if they could, those prisoners who aren't killed when you blast open the wall
就算可以，当你炸墙时，那些未死的战俘
would be scattered throughout the castle,
会分散在整个城堡
locked up in dozens of cubbyholes and cellars.
被锁在幽闭的暗室和地下室
You'd need a force that could subdue the German garrison
你要有力量打败德国的防守部队
and stand off reinforcements from outside.
并抵住外面的援军
No. I applaud your motives but your scheme is impracticable.
不行，我赞赏你的想法，但你的计划不合实际
Giving men a chance for their lives is impracticable?
给别人生存的机会不合实际？
You have a particular emotional involvement with these prisoners.
你对这些战俘有特殊的感情困扰
Have you thought about the men on the ground you're asking to risk their lives?
你想过你派去地面冒险的人的性命吗？
Nothing must be attempted that would jeopardise the aim of the strike.
会危及主要攻击计划的都不能实行
Supposing...
如果...
Supposing, just before we blow the wall,
如果只是在我们炸毁那墙之前，
that the prisoners could be gathered together in one safe place.
那些战俘能集中在一个安全的地方
Couldn't the underground take them over and get them out on the escape route?
地下游击队不能接收他们然后帮助他们逃离出去吗？
Most of those that survive, I would say.
我认为这样的话，大部分的人会幸存下来
Then schedule the attack for Sunday morning.
那么安排在星期天早上进攻吧
Sunday morning?
星期天早上？
(Morse bleeps)
（摩斯密码）
Sunday morning. Of course. Of course.
星期天早上，当然，当然
- Mon pe, qu'est-ce que c'est?    - N'importe. Allez, dhez-vous.
- 神父，什么事？   - 无论什么事，走吧
- Morning.    - Morning, padre.
- 早上好    - 早上好，神父
Good day.
祝你开心，孩子
Morning, Father.
早上好，神父
Ah, Lieutenant Schack, bonjour.
斯加克中尉，你好
Bonjour, Father Bellague. The confessional is all ready for you.
早上好，贝拉格神父，已为你准备好忏悔室了
Thank you.
谢谢
Please remove your guards. I cannot ask these men
请你撤掉你的警卫，我不能叫这些人
to confess to God with a gun at their backs.
拿着枪在背后指吓时招供
Sorry, Father. The commandant's orders.
对不起，神父，这是司令部的命令
I think he suspects you give out more than absolution in the confessional.
我想他怀疑你会说和告解无关的话
Perhaps he'd prefer me to hear my confessions in the open,
或许他想我在室外聆听告解
where his entire garrison could watch?
好让所有的防备兵监视
As you please, Father.
神父，如果你喜欢也可以
Geben Sie mir einen Stuhl.
我到外面去
Tu, was er sagt.
先搬椅子出去
Here.
放这儿
- Give me your blessing, for I have sinned.    - Keep your lips moving and listen.
- 愿主保佑，我犯罪了    - 你继续说话，并且小心听着
I will not repeat this.
我不会重说
Tell all your men they are to be at Mass in chapel on Sunday morning.
告诉所有人，叫他们星期天早上去小礼拜堂做弥撒
Tell them that the order is from Air Command.
告诉他们命令是从空军司令部发出
Now, my son.
我的孩子，现在
For I have sinned. Through my fault.
我犯了罪，宽恕我的罪
Through my most grievous fault.
宽恕我最严重的错
(gives blessing)
（祝福）
Go in peace and pray for me.
平静下来，为我们祈祷吧
Keep your lips moving, son, and listen carefully.
孩子，继续说话，并且小心听着
When all the men are in chapel tomorrow morning and the attack begins,
明早，当所有人在小礼拜堂内，轰炸开始时，
- they are trying to get you out.    - Thank God!
- 他们会试图救出你们    - 感谢天主
Gentlemen, this mission must be executed with exacting precision,
先生们，这任务必须非常精确才能实现
both in timing and accuracy.
在于时间的配合和进攻准确度
This tunnel... must be closed.
这条隧道...必须炸掉
Munroe, Clarke and Bannister will fly the first phase.
文路，克拉克和班尼斯特首先飞出
Each of their Mosquitoes will carry two highball bombs,
每架蚊式战斗机会带两枚炸弹
one of which is capable of destroying the entire underground facility.
每一架都能摧毁整个地下道
Munroe, as soon as one of you puts a bomb into the mouth of the tunnel,
文路，你们尽快地把炸弹投进隧道，
you may proceed to breach the wall.
因而你可以炸墙
The prisoners will be waiting in the chapel.
战俘们会在小礼拜堂等候
Once the wall is destroyed,
墙一倒下，
the French underground will start diversionary skirmishes
法国的地下游击队就会开始小战争来引开他们注意力
so that our men will have a chance to head for the woods to the west.
使我们的人有机会逃跑到西边的树林
Minutes later, waves of Mosquitoes will level Charlon.
几分钟后，蚊式飞机群将会摧毁沙尔龙堡
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Takeoff at 0625 hours tomorrow.
明天6点25分出发
Dismissed.
解散
Looks as though it's going to be pretty sloppy over Charlon.
沙尔龙堡上空看上去好像多云
Damned rain could ruin what little chances we did have.
讨厌的雨会毁坏我们的良机
Rain or no rain, we go tomorrow.
不管有没有雨，我们明天都要出发
Did Intelligence tell us how to get a decent bounce off this muck?
情报部门告诉我们怎样避开这些讨厌的东西吗？
Yeah. Just before you shoot, you use my guaranteed equaliser.
对，在你射击前，用我的平衡器
What's that?
那是什么？
Just before you shoot, you spit on your firing thumb.
在你射击前，吐口水在拇指上
What's so hilarious, chum?
有什么好笑的？
I've been a bit worried about him recently.
我最近有点担心他
- He was getting serious about his job.    - Is that so bad?
- 他对他的工作更认真   - 那很糟糕吗？
When a man like Quint Munroe gets serious, he gets cautious.
当像昆特文路这样的人认真时，他就会小心谨慎
- That's when his luck deserts him.    - And us?
- 那就是好运抛弃他的时候   - 我们呢？
And us.
我们也是
Hey!
嘿！
- They won't let me see Douglas.    - I thought you knew that already.
- 他们不准我见道格拉斯   - 我想你已知道了
I thought if I came here to the base, I...
我想如果我从基地来这里，我...
I had to see you, Quint.
我一定要见你，昆特
Well, I... I can't stay long.
我...我不能久留
Can't you tell me why he's confined to his quarters? Why I can't speak to him?
你能不能告诉我他为什么被软禁在房内？我为何不能和他说话？
- Insubordination.    - That's not true. To whom?
- 他违抗命令   - 那不是真的，违抗谁？
The wing commander.
违抗空军司令部
I... I shouldn't have come here.
我真不该来这里
When will I see you again?
我什么时候可以再见到你?
Tomorrow.
明天
With luck?
祝你好运
Come back, Quint. I couldn't bear it if you didn't.
昆特，你要回来。你不回来的话我不能承受
Stand easy, please.
请稍息
Don't worry, I'm going to spare you my usual tedious pep talk.
别担心，我这次不会象往常那样说闷话了
You know the importance of your mission.
通知你们了，你们知道任务的重要性
Just remember that our bomber wave will start their drop at precisely 1000 hours,
只要记住我们的轰炸机攻势会在精确的1000分钟内开始投弹，
regardless of whether or not all our prisoners are out of Charlon.
不管是否所有战俘都逃出沙尔龙堡
So any delay in dealing with the targets assigned to you could be very costly.
在处理命令要求击中的目标中，如果有延误的话，会有极大伤亡
That's all I wanted to say, except to wish each of you good luck.
祝你们好运，我的话讲完了
(horn honks)
(汽车的喇叭声)
'Shun!
立正！
Good morning, gentlemen.
早上好，各位
Stand easy.
稍息
I'm told the weather over Charlon will be ideal for our purposes today.
我被告知，沙尔龙堡上空的天气很适合我们的计划
- Everyone feeling well?    - Yes, thank you, sir.
- 大家的身体好吗？   - 好，谢谢，长官
- Perhaps you'd better break this news.    - As you wish, Wing Commander.
- 或许你可以通告这个消息    - 可以的，空军司令
It's from the air marshal. A slight change in your orders.
来自空军执行官的话，你们的命令有些改变
You are not to attack the prison wall until you have successfully sealed that tunnel.
你们要在成功切断隧道后，才能炸毁狱墙
What if it takes all six highballs to do the job?
要是用完了6枚炸弹才完成任务怎么办？
Then, regrettably, the escape plan is aborted.
那很遗憾，救人计划就会被取消
- The underground was told to withdraw.   - Our chaps will be blown to hell.
- 地下队员会被通知撤退   - 我们的伙伴会被炸死？
The tunnel has first priority. The escape plan is a bonus operation.
隧道是要优先处理的，救人计划是额外的行动
It made sense with a highball for the prison, but this is obscene!
炸弹对战俘们来说很重要，但这很讨厌！
That's enough! There will be no deviation from the air marshal's orders.
够了！空军执行官的命令是不会有错的
Is that clear, Squadron Leader Munroe?
明白吗，文路空军队长？
Sir.
是，长官
I'm sure you'll have several highballs to spare for that wall, Munroe.
文路，我肯定你们会留有炸弹去炸那墙
- I feel confident of that.    - I'm glad you do, sir.
- 我对这有信心    - 长官，我为此感到高兴
Carry on, Wing Commander.
继续吧，长官
All right.
行了
- You know the trouble with this war, sir?    - What?
- 长官，你知道这战争的麻烦吗？   - 什么？
The world's back to front.
世界就在前面
- Back to front?    - Yeah.
- 就在前面？   - 是
We go out and the sun's rising in our face.
太阳升起的时候我们出发
We come home and it's setting in our face.
日落的时候我们就回家
Yeah. The world's back to front.
对，世界就在前面
- I bet the Luftwaffe doesn't think so.    - Ah!
- 我想德国空军不这样认为，维利   - 是！
They had years preparing for this rotten war. We just got it handed to us.
他们准备这场残忍的战争好几年了。我们要得到赞扬
(church bell tolls)
(教堂的钟声)
Suddenly, Father, everyone is very religious.
神父，很突然，所有人都很虔诚
You!
你！
He can't even remember his name. How does he know he's a Catholic?
他甚至不记得自己的名字。他怎知自己是天主教徒？
The Spirit moves in mysterious ways, Lieutenant Schack.
斯加克中尉，灵魂以其神奇的形式支配思想
Go.
走吧
The commandant is not so difficult to understand.
要了解司令官并不是那么难
The commandant dislikes mysterious occurrences.
司令官不喜欢神秘运作的事情
Take care, Priest.
神父，小心
- Squadron Leader?    - Yes, Father?
- 空军队长？   - 是的，神父
You, erm... You do not know your name?
你...你不知道自己的名字？
No, Father.
神父，不记得
Please, take your seat, my son.
请就坐，我的孩子
If anything ever puts me off religion, this will.
这会使我从此信教的
- What's happening?    - Escape.
- 发生什么事了？   - 逃跑
- Who says so?    - I do. The old priest's up to something.
- 谁说的？   - 我说的，老神父就是为这而来
That's right. He's gonna sneak us out under his robes.
对，他将要用长袍把我们偷走
- All of us?    - We're going home.
- 我们所有人？   - 我们都回家去
- How's Daisy?    - Don't ask.
- 戴茜怎么样？   - 别问了
Now what?
怎么了？
- She lost the ration books again    - we're starving to death!
- 她又丢了粮簿    - 我们要饿死了
Still, she makes up for it in other ways.
但她从另一方面补偿了
(priest administers Mass)
(神父在做弥撒)
Five minutes to target.
距目标有5分钟路程
New course, 160... now!
新方向，160... 现在！
(air-raid siren)
(空袭警报)
Out, out, out, out! Everyone back to his cell!
出去，出去！各自回到牢房
Squadron Leader Neale!
空军队长尼尔！
You're a senior officer here.
你是这儿的高级军官
Order your men to march outside at once... please!
请命令你的属下立即出去！
Stay where you are, men. That's an order.
大家留下来，这是命令
So we have a mutiny on our hands.
我们就要发生兵变了
Priest!
神父！
Tell them to obey!
叫他们服从！
You're a foolish man, Father Bellague.
神父贝拉格，你是个傻子
You insist on being a martyr!
你坚持要当烈士
You fascist!
你这个王八蛋！
Barricade the door!
堵住门！
- He's dead.    - Take him to the sacristy.
- 他死了    - 抬他到收藏室
Now, men! Men!
各位！
Men, listen to me!
大家听我说！
Gather round and listen.
集合给我听着
- We've been ordered to stay here.    - We can't stay holed up here, sir.
- 我们奉命留在这里。   - 长官，我们没有武器，不能躲在这里
We'll stick it as long as we can. Now settle down. Back to your seats!
我们要尽量坚持。现在静下来，回到座位上
Hound Master to Pack, one minute to target.
猎人呼叫猎犬，还有1分钟到目标
(Quint) I'll drop first at 60 feet, 1,000 yards out.
我将在1000码，60尺上空投下第一枚炸弹
Watch how I bounce and compensate accordingly. Over.
仔细看我怎样投弹，然后照做，完毕
Roger. Good luck, Quint!
收到。祝你好运，昆特！
Air scoop out!
打开弹舱
Air scoop out, sir.
长官，开启了
- RPM?    - 6-5-0. 700.
- 飞行速度？   - 650，700
Stand by.
预备
Steady. Steady.
保持稳定
Bomb away!
投弹！
Dog One to Hound Master. I'm going to drop from 75 feet at 1100.
猎犬1号呼叫猎人，我将用1100下降75英尺
Bomb away!
投弹！
Dog Two from Hound Master. Same height at 1200. Over.
猎犬2号呼叫猎人，在同样高度1200，完毕
Roger.
收到
Bandits on your tail, sir. Bandits!
敌机在10点后面，长官，敌机！
We're down to two shots, Bannister. We've still got two targets.
班尼斯特，我们只剩2个炸弹，我们还有两个目标
Then I'd better make this one good.
这次我必须击准
Dog One! Dog One!
猎犬1号！猎犬1号！
Bannister! Are you all right?
班尼斯特！你没事吧？
Bannister. Are you all right?
Better get started for that prison wall, chum.
老友，最好开始轰炸监狱墙
Everything's under control here.
这里一切正常
Make it good, Wiley. It's their only chance.
维利，击准，这是他们唯一的机会
(shouts order)
(大声命令)
They're gonna blast us out.
他们要炸开这里
This is suicide. We've got to get out, sir.
这简直就是自杀。长官，我们必须出去
No! Hang on until the last moment.
不行！坚持到最后一刻
Stand by!
预备
(Wiley) Hold it. Hold it.
稳住，稳住
Bomb away!
投弹
Come on!
走吧！
Viens ici!
到这儿来！
Vite, vite!
快，快！
Wiley!
维利！
Scotty?
斯科特？
The tank! Get it! Get it!
坦克！拿下它！
Scotty, it's me! It's me - Quint.
斯科特，是我，昆特！
Who?
谁？
- Scotty!    - What did you call me?
- 斯科特！   - 你叫我什么？
Someone's gonna have to get that tank!
必须有人抢到那坦克
You're Squadron Leader David Scott. You've gotta remember!
你是空军队长，大卫斯科特，记得吧！
Beth!
贝丝
Got us pinned down, that tank. Gotta get across that road.
我们被这坦克困住。得过去那边
Here, give me that.
给我那个
Scotty!
斯科特！
That tank!
坦克！
You've gotta listen to me.
你得听我说
听我说
Scotty, what about Beth?
斯科特，贝丝怎么办？
Scotty!
斯科特！
Beth.
贝丝
Scotty!
斯科特！
Parade, 'shun!
列队，立正！
- Morning, sir.   - Good morning.
- 早上好，长官   - 早上好
This lot were picked up from the beach last night by a submarine.
这个是昨晚被一艘潜艇在海湾救起的
They've just flown in from Southampton.
他们从南安普敦漂流过来
The mission was a success. Just the casualties are so damnably bad.
这项任务很成功。只是伤亡非常惨重
(Doug) Quint!
昆特！
Thank God. Scotty?
谢天谢地
He was killed.
他阵亡了
Does, er...
有...
Does Beth know he was alive?
贝丝知道他还活着吗？
No.
不知道
Munroe, well done.
文路，干得非常好
What you and the others did, my boy, was historic.
你们所做的是多么有历史意义
Yes, and costly. We lost Bannister and Clarke.
对，可是损失惨重，我们失去了班尼斯和克拉克
(Hufford) But Germany will always remember Charlon.
但是德国人会永远记住沙尔龙堡，永远不会忘记
(Penrose) There'll be another squadron. There'll never be another Charlon.
还会有另一个空军部队的，昆特。但永远不会有另一个沙尔龙堡了
If you'll excuse me, sir.
长官，请原谅
THE END
剧终